Have you ever wondered on how often you should wear your night guard?
Well my name is Michelle and I'm a dental assistant with Solutionz and I'm here to explain to you on how often you should wear it.
Basically if you have been prescribed by your general dentist to wear a night guard because you tend to maybe grind your teeth at night, or to wear a night guard during the day while you're driving 'cause you get tense and you grind your teeth.
But that's something - wearing a night guard is something you definitely want to wear on a consistent basis every night.
It's pretty easy after you brush and floss your teeth before you go to bed, you just pop in your night guard, wear it for those eight hours or six hours of sleep that you're getting.
And then take it out in the morning, rinse it off, even maybe you know rinse it off with your toothbrush and toothpaste, to kind of keep it clean of that excess film that you might have left on it.
But if you've been prescribed by your general dentist to wear a night guard you definitely want to wear it every night on a regular basis because by doing so you're going to be training your actual jaw joints to kind of not become so tense.
You have to basically you're retraining those TMJ joints to kind of stay propped open and you're providing cushion for them, so the more that you can wear it the better it will be for you in the long run, but yes, every night definitely wear your night guard if you've been prescribed to wear it during driving, every time you get in the car, pop it in.
It's only going to be a benefit for you in the future.
Once again my name is Michelle and I'm a dental assistant with Solutionz, and I just explained to you on how often to wear your night guard.